<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systemic on Anthropocene Timeline</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/tags/systemic/</link><description>Recent content in Systemic on Anthropocene Timeline</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Anthropocene Timeline. All rights reserved.</copyright><atom:link href="https://anthropocenetimeline.com/tags/systemic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Earthmasters</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/earthmasters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/earthmasters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Deconstruction of the myth of geo-engineering solutions and explains how some people want to play god with the climate.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ecological Threat Report</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ecologicalthreatregister/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ecologicalthreatregister/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ETR 2020 results show that 141 countries are exposed to
at least one ecological threat between now and 2050.
The 19 countries with the highest number of threats
have a population of 2.1 billion people. These countries
face four to six ecological threats and more than half
are among the 40 least peaceful nations. The three
countries with the highest exposure to ecological
shocks are Afghanistan, which is facing six ecological
threats and Mozambique and Namibia, which are each
facing five. Another 16 countries are facing four
ecological threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Facing the Collapse</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/devantleffondrement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/devantleffondrement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A hard-to-read book because of the conclusion it suggests : a collapse of our society probably in 2020 and certain before 2030.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Global Climate Report</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/noaaglobalclimatereport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/noaaglobalclimatereport/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2023 was the warmest year since global records began in 1850 at 1.18°C (2.12°F) above the 20th century average of 13.9°C (57.0°F). This value is 0.15°C (0.27°F) more than the previous record set in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 10 warmest years in the 174-year record have all occurred during the last decade (2014–2023).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of note, the year 2005, which was the first year to set a new global temperature record in the 21st century, is now the 12th-warmest year on record.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Global Decline of Insects</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/declineofinsects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/declineofinsects/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The authors used a standardized protocol to measure total insect biomassusing Malaise traps, deployed over 27 years in 63 nature protection areas in Germany (96unique location-year combinations) to infer on the status and trend of local entomofauna. Our analysis estimates a seasonal decline of 76%, and mid-summer decline of 82% in flyinginsect biomass over the 27 years of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show that this decline is apparent regardless of habitat type, while changes in weather, land use, and habitat characteristics cannot explain this overall decline. This yet unrecognized loss of insect biomass must be taken into account in evaluating declines in abundance of species depending on insects as a foodsource, and ecosystem functioning in the European landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Humanity in peril</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/humaniteenperilvironsdebord/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/humaniteenperilvironsdebord/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fred Vargas is mostly well-known for her crime novels however she wrote a transparent and really easy to read (even for neophytes) book about the systemic problems due to Anthropocene. The book is quite naive and its approach is sometimes confusing but it at least informs people about climate change, biodiversity destruction, energy and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Living Planet Report</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/livingplanetreport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/livingplanetreport/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Living Planet Report 2020 clearly
outlines how humanity’s increasing destruction of nature is having
catastrophic impacts not only on wildlife populations but also on
human health and all aspects of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This highlights that a deep cultural and systemic shift is urgently
needed, one that so far our civilisation has failed to embrace: a
transition to a society and economic system that values nature,
stops taking it for granted and recognises that we depend on nature
more than nature depends on us.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Net Zero by 2050</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/netzeroby2050/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/netzeroby2050/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The number of countries announcing pledges to achieve net zero emissions over the coming decades continues to grow. But the pledges by governments to date – even if fully achieved – fall well short of what is required to bring global energy-related carbon dioxide emissions to net zero by 2050 and give the world an even chance of limiting the global temperature rise to 1.5 °C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This special report is the world’s first comprehensive study of how to transition to a net zero energy system by 2050 while ensuring stable and affordable energy supplies, providing universal energy access, and enabling robust economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Only One Earth</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/onlyoneearth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/onlyoneearth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This book was originally produced in 1972 as a report commissioned by the Secretary-General of the United Nations Conference on the Human Environment. It was prepared with help from 152 committee members from 58 countries. As well as being something of a classic, it is fascinating to read it 50 years later, containing as it does a range of accurate predictions, warnings and suggestions – much of which have been ignored for half a century. The broad outcome is that, had the world paid attention to its contents and taken suitable action, we would not be in the mess we are in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Planetary Boundaries</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/planetaryboundaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/planetaryboundaries/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Earth beyond six of nine planetary boundaries&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sleep quietly until 2100</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/dormeztranquillesjusquen2100/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/dormeztranquillesjusquen2100/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A book har to read in my opinion as it goes in all directions, left and right, with a confusing structure. I would better recommend Jean-Marc Jancovici&amp;rsquo;s conferences (available on Youtube for example): he is clearer orally.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Brundtland report</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ourcommonfuture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ourcommonfuture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This report is &amp;ldquo;A global agenda for change&amp;rdquo; - this was what the World Commission on Environment and
Development was asked to formulate. It was an urgent call by the General Assembly of the
United Nations: to propose long-term environmental strategies for achieving sustainable development
by the year 2000 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Great Acceleration</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/thegreatacceleration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/thegreatacceleration/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ‘Great Acceleration’ graphs, originally published in 2004 to show socio-economic and Earth System trends from 1750 to 2000, have now been updated to 2010. In the graphs of socio-economic trends, where the data permit, the activity of the wealthy (OECD) countries, those countries with emerging economies, and the rest of the world have now been differentiated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominant feature of the socio-economic trends is that the economic activity of the human enterprise continues to grow at a rapid rate. However, the differentiated graphs clearly show that strong equity issues are masked by considering global aggregates only. Most of the population growth since 1950 has been in the non-OECD world but the world’s economy (GDP), and hence consumption, is still strongly dominated by the OECD world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Limits to Growth</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thelimitstogrowth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thelimitstogrowth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A classic and a must-read. New editions have been published in 1992, 2004 and 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Low Tech Era</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/agedeslowtech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/agedeslowtech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A focus on the ressource part of the systemic concern in the Anthropocene in particular about metals and rare ressources used in our High Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The New Plastics Economy</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/thenewplasticseconomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/thenewplasticseconomy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The report explores plastics and plastic
packaging issues in particular: how can collaboration along the extended global plastic
packaging production and after-use value chain, as well as with governments
and NGOs, achieve systemic change to overcome stalemates in today’s plastics
economy in order to move to a more circular model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Plastics Economy aims to set an initial direction and contribute to the
evidence base by synthesizing information from across many dispersed sources.
It assesses the benefits and drawbacks of plastic packaging today, and makes
the case for rethinking the current plastics economy. It lays out the ambitions and
benefits of the New Plastics Economy – a system aiming to achieve drastically
better economic and environmental outcomes. It proposes a new approach and
action plan to get there.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Unhabitable Earth</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/unhabitableearth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/unhabitableearth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The book explores various possibilities for Earth&amp;rsquo;s future across a spectrum of predicted future temperature ranges. Wallace-Wells&amp;rsquo; argues that even with active intervention, the effects of climate change will have catastrophic impacts across multiple spheres.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thinking about degrowth</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/penserladecroissance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/penserladecroissance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A book written by different specialists where each has its own chapter. There are two books that follow after this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>This Changes Everything</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thischangeseverything/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thischangeseverything/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a must-read in order to understand the systemic causes and consequences in the Anthropocene.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trajectories of the Earth System</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/trajectoriesearthsystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/trajectoriesearthsystem/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We explore the risk that self-reinforcing feedbacks could push the Earth System toward a planetary threshold that, if crossed, could prevent stabilization of the climate at intermediate temperature rises and cause continued warming on a “Hothouse Earth” pathway even as human emissions are reduced.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>