<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Politics on Anthropocene Timeline</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in Politics on Anthropocene Timeline</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://anthropocenetimeline.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Govern the Climate</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/gouvernerleclimat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/gouvernerleclimat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a great book that goes through the history of all the international conferences about climate change and shows how and why things have not evolved.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IEA World Energy Outlook reports</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/iea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/iea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The IEA’s flagship World Energy Outlook (WEO) is the most authoritative source of global energy analysis and projections. Updated annually to reflect the latest energy data, technology and market trends, and government policies, it explores a range of possible energy futures and their implications for energy security, access and emissions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IPCC reports</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ipcc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ipcc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The most important and reliable scientific source about climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Merchants of Doubt</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/merchantsofdoubt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/merchantsofdoubt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;How a Handful of Scientists Obscured the Truth on Issues from Tobacco Smoke to Global Warming.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Net Zero by 2050</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/netzeroby2050/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/netzeroby2050/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The number of countries announcing pledges to achieve net zero emissions over the coming decades continues to grow. But the pledges by governments to date – even if fully achieved – fall well short of what is required to bring global energy-related carbon dioxide emissions to net zero by 2050 and give the world an even chance of limiting the global temperature rise to 1.5 °C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This special report is the world’s first comprehensive study of how to transition to a net zero energy system by 2050 while ensuring stable and affordable energy supplies, providing universal energy access, and enabling robust economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Only One Earth</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/onlyoneearth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/onlyoneearth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This book was originally produced in 1972 as a report commissioned by the Secretary-General of the United Nations Conference on the Human Environment. It was prepared with help from 152 committee members from 58 countries. As well as being something of a classic, it is fascinating to read it 50 years later, containing as it does a range of accurate predictions, warnings and suggestions – much of which have been ignored for half a century. The broad outcome is that, had the world paid attention to its contents and taken suitable action, we would not be in the mess we are in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Scenario for the derivation of global CO2 reduction targets and implementation strategies</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/wbgu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/wbgu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The conclusions of the scenario are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthropogenic emissions must be reduced to almost zero over the
very long term, i.e. within a period of several centuries. The climate
system permits a considerable amount of freedom with respect to how
the emission profile is actually shaped, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current emission patterns could be continued for another 25 years
(“Business As Usual”), but this would then demand such drastic
reduction measures within only a few years that the structures and
technologies capable of producing such levels of abatement are not
even remotely conceivable at present.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Brundtland report</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ourcommonfuture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/ourcommonfuture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This report is &amp;ldquo;A global agenda for change&amp;rdquo; - this was what the World Commission on Environment and
Development was asked to formulate. It was an urgent call by the General Assembly of the
United Nations: to propose long-term environmental strategies for achieving sustainable development
by the year 2000 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The New Plastics Economy</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/thenewplasticseconomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/thenewplasticseconomy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The report explores plastics and plastic
packaging issues in particular: how can collaboration along the extended global plastic
packaging production and after-use value chain, as well as with governments
and NGOs, achieve systemic change to overcome stalemates in today’s plastics
economy in order to move to a more circular model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Plastics Economy aims to set an initial direction and contribute to the
evidence base by synthesizing information from across many dispersed sources.
It assesses the benefits and drawbacks of plastic packaging today, and makes
the case for rethinking the current plastics economy. It lays out the ambitions and
benefits of the New Plastics Economy – a system aiming to achieve drastically
better economic and environmental outcomes. It proposes a new approach and
action plan to get there.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Stern Review</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/thesternreview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/thesternreview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This Review has assessed a wide range of evidence on the impacts of climate
change and on the economic costs, and has used a number of different techniques to
assess costs and risks. From all of these perspectives, the evidence gathered by the
Review leads to a simple conclusion: the benefits of strong and early action far
outweigh the economic costs of not acting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate change will affect the basic elements of life for people around the world –
access to water, food production, health, and the environment. Hundreds of millions
of people could suffer hunger, water shortages and coastal flooding as the world
warms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thinking about degrowth</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/penserladecroissance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/penserladecroissance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A book written by different specialists where each has its own chapter. There are two books that follow after this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>This Changes Everything</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thischangeseverything/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thischangeseverything/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a must-read in order to understand the systemic causes and consequences in the Anthropocene.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Turn Down the Heat</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/turndowntheheat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/turndowntheheat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report synthesizing the latest scientific knowledge on global warming warns we’re
on a path to a 4 degree Celsius warmer world by the end of the century—with huge implications for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>