<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Energy on Anthropocene Timeline</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/tags/energy/</link><description>Recent content in Energy on Anthropocene Timeline</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Anthropocene Timeline. All rights reserved.</copyright><atom:link href="https://anthropocenetimeline.com/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Gold</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/ornoir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/ornoir/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;An essay about oil history, from its discovery to its importance in today&amp;rsquo;s civilization in all domains: industrial of course but also military, political and economical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carbon Bombs</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/carbonbombs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/papers/carbonbombs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Meeting the Paris targets requires reducing both fossil fuel demand and supply, and closing the “production gap” between climate targets and energy policy. But there is no supply-side mitigation roadmap yet. We need criteria to decide where to focus efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we identify the 425 biggest fossil fuel extraction projects globally (defined as &amp;gt;1 gigaton potential CO2 emissions). We list these “carbon bombs” by name, show in which countries they are located and calculate their potential emissions which combined exceed the global 1.5 °C carbon budget by a factor of two. Already producing carbon bombs account for a significant percentage of global fossil fuel extraction. But 40% of carbon bombs have not yet started extraction.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IEA World Energy Outlook reports</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/iea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/reports/iea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The IEA’s flagship World Energy Outlook (WEO) is the most authoritative source of global energy analysis and projections. Updated annually to reflect the latest energy data, technology and market trends, and government policies, it explores a range of possible energy futures and their implications for energy security, access and emissions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sleep quietly until 2100</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/dormeztranquillesjusquen2100/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/dormeztranquillesjusquen2100/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A book har to read in my opinion as it goes in all directions, left and right, with a confusing structure. I would better recommend Jean-Marc Jancovici&amp;rsquo;s conferences (available on Youtube for example): he is clearer orally.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Coal Question</title><link>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thecoalquestion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropocenetimeline.com/sources/books/thecoalquestion/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The central thesis was that the supremacy of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland over global affairs was transitory, given the finite nature of its primary energy resource. In propounding this thesis, Jevons covered a range of issues central to sustainability, including limits to growth, overpopulation, overshoot, energy return on energy input (EROEI), taxation of energy resources, renewable energy alternatives, and resource peaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>